A Guide to the Defective surveys, A-Z, from the Virginia Land Office, 1761-1872
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Defective surveys, A-Z, from the Virginia Land Office, 1761-1872
The Library of Virginia
LOI 46
2.7 cu. ft. (6 boxes)
Virginia. Land Office
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession LOI 46 transferred by the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1948.
Historical Information
The act which established the previous Land Office passed the General Assembly on 22 June 1779. The register was the head of the Office and was appointed by joint ballot of both houses of the legislature. The office of the Superintendent of Weights and Measures was abolished by an act of 7 February 1867, and his duties were transferred to the register of the Land Office. The records of the Land Office which were in the custody of the Secretary of the Commonwealth were transferred to the State Library, and, by Act of Assembly on 5 March 1952, the duties of the regsiter of the Land Office were transferred from the Secretary of the Commonwealth to the state librarian.
Scope and Content
Surveys which were not carried into grants because of technical defects. Among the more common defects are the use of depleted warrants, the use of warrants issued after the survey was returned, and the omission of the names of persons participating in the survey. These surveys give the names of the person for whom the survey was returned and the surveyor and his assistants, the name of the county in which the land was located and a description of that land, the type and number of the warrant employed, and the date on which the survey was made.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Virginia. Land Office
Subjects:
Surveying -- Virginia.
Genre and Form Terms:
Land surveys -- Virginia -- Washington County.; State government records -- Virginia
Contents List
- Defective Surveys, 1750-1872., Extent: 6 boxes (2.7 cu. ft.). (Box 1-6)
  Alphabetical
  - Defective Surveys, A, 1791-1865. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Defective Surveys, Ba-Bl, 1791-1868. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Defective Surveys, Bo, 1780-1840. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Defective Surveys, Br-By, 1791-1852. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Defective Surveys, Ca-Ch, 1782-1872. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Defective Surveys, Cl-Cu, 1780-1851. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Defective Surveys, D, 1768-1849. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Defective Surveys, E, 1794-1840. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Defective Surveys, F, 1782-1842. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Defective Surveys, G, 1773-1851. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Defective Surveys, Ha, 1782-1862. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Defective Surveys, He-Hu, 1769-1846. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Defective Surveys, I, 1768-1824. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Defective Surveys, J, 1781-1841. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Defective Surveys, K, 1775-1838. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Defective Surveys, La-Le, 1774-1851. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Defective Surveys, Li-Ly, 1750-1833. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Defective Surveys, Ma-Me, 1771-1846. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Defective Surveys, Mi-Mu, 1761-1838. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Defective Surveys, N, 1788-1840. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Defective Surveys, O, 1796-1828. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Defective Surveys, P, 1774-1840. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Defective Surveys, Q, 1797. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Defective Surveys, R, 1784-1853. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Defective Surveys, Sa-Se, 1773-1846. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Defective Surveys, Sm-Sy, 1783-1865. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Defective Surveys, T, 1782-1862. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Defective Surveys, V, 1789-1841. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Defective Surveys, Wa-Wh, 1780-1865. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Defective Surveys, We-Wy, 1771-1842. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Defective Surveys, Y, 1795-1837. (Box 6, Folder 5)